### **Angkush Kumar Ghosh**

#### Address:

090-0801, Japan, Hokkaido, Kitami City,

Shunko-Cho 7-Chome 62-12 Shunko-Cho Shukusha 504-22

**Phone:** +81 (0)80 1866 0594

**Email:** angkush\_ghosh@outlook.com, ghosh-ak@mail.kitami-it.ac.jp

Website: https://ghosh-ak.github.io/



#### **SUMMARY**

As an Assistant Professor at Kitami Institute of Technology (KIT), Japan, I am affiliated with the Division of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering and the Advanced Manufacturing Engineering Laboratory. My primary responsibilities include teaching undergraduate courses in CAD/CAM and conducting research. My research interests lie in AI, Machine Learning, and Intelligent Systems for Smart Manufacturing / Industry 4.0, as well as exploring future advancements in the field. Alongside my academic roles, I have gained valuable experience in project management, effective communication, collaboration, and various administrative tasks throughout my career. In my leisure time, I enjoy immersing myself in music, following football matches passionately, reading various genres, and traveling to new destinations to embrace diverse cultures.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Assistant Professor,**

Division of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, Advanced Manufacturing Engineering Laboratory, Kitami Institute of Technology, Japan Responsibilities:

- Teaching undergraduate courses: CAD/CAM.
- Researching.
- Supervising students.

9/2015 - 9/2017

#### Coordinator and Lecturer,

Department of Mechanical Engineering, Sonargaon University, Bangladesh Responsibilities:

- Coordinating departmental and administrative affairs.
- Student counseling.
- Teaching undergraduate courses: CAD, C Programming, Mechanical Engineering Drawing, Production Processes.

3/2015 - 9/2015

#### Service Engineer,

MBioLogix, Bangladesh

Responsibilities:

- Installing, calibrating, and servicing instruments & machinery used in medical industry (clinics, hospitals, pharmaceuticals, research institutions, medical colleges, and alike) in Bangladesh.
- Training end-users about operation and regular maintenance.
- Creating user-oriented standard operating procedure (SOP).

4/2022 - Present

#### **Physics Tutor,**

Anushilon Education Centre, Bangladesh

Responsibilities:

- Preparing lecture notes.
- Teaching and assessing.

3/2014 - 6/2014

#### Assistant Engineer,

Navana Construction Ltd., Bangladesh

Responsibilities:

- Site supervision and project management.
- Surveying site area.
- Assessing and modifying the designed layout.
- Communicating with different stakeholders and coordinating the tasks.
- Maintaining the material flow.
- Billing of subcontractors.
- Technical support.

## INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

Intern,

LEXER RESEARCH Inc., Japan

5/2021 - 8/2021

9/2021 - 12/2021

Intern,

Advanced Manufacturing Research Institute (AMRI), National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology (AIST), Japan

#### **EDUCATION**

10/2019 - 3/2022

**Doctor of Engineering in Manufacturing Engineering,** 

Kitami Institute of Technology, Japan

10/2017 - 9/2019

Master of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering,

Kitami Institute of Technology, Japan

3/2009 - 10/2013

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) in Mechanical Engineering,

Khulna University of Engineering and Technology, Bangladesh

**RESEARCH** 

ORCID 🔗

Google Scholar: 🔗

Laboratory Website 🔗

Personal Website 🔗

# PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

- The Japan Society for Precision Engineering (JSPE)
  Member since 4/2022
- The Japan Society of Mechanical Engineers (JSME) Member since 10/2019

#### ACADEMIC SERVICE

- o JSME iDECON/MS 2023: Program Committee Member
- o Reviewer for Various Academic Journals

**HOBBIES** • Music • Football • Reading • Traveling

**REFERENCE** References are available upon request.